Guide to the Rainbow Kitchen Records, 1974-1992 AIS.1991.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rainbow Kitchen Records
1974-1992
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rainbow Kitchen
AIS.1991.10
50 Linear Feet (31 boxes and 102 oversize items)
Rainbow Kitchen Community Services was founded in 1984 by Bob Anderson, Theresa Chalich and Dolores Patrick, in response to the devastating community impact of the closing of area steel mills, which displaced thousands of workers living near Pittsburgh, Pa. This collection contains the records of Bob Anderson regarding the Rainbow Kitchen and other organizations which aimed to help unemployed steelworkers in the Pittsburgh area during the 1980s.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert L. Anderson in July 1991.
Previous Citation
Rainbow Kitchen Records, 1974-1992, AIS.1991.10, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
The job bank applications in Box 23 are closed for 75 years from date of creation. Until this restriction is lifted, researchers must sign a confidentiality agreement to access the records. Please contact the Archives Service Center for more information.
History
Rainbow Kitchen Community Services was founded in 1984 by Bob Anderson, Theresa Chalich and Dolores Patrick, in response to the devastating community impact of the closing of area steel mills, which displaced thousands of workers living near Pittsburgh, Pa. Originally known as the Homestead Unemployed Center, the Rainbow Kitchen aims to help low income families become self sufficient through its food pantry, job training classes and other programs. Still located in Homestead, Pa., the non-profit is supported mostly through private donations, grants, and fundraising efforts.
Related Material
Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Records, 1980-1995, AIS.2002.02, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the records of Bob Anderson regarding the Rainbow Kitchen and other organizations which aimed to help unemployed steelworkers in the Pittsburgh area during the 1980s. Included is information on the steel industry and labor union locals, as well as publications concerning deindustrialization and the political left. Files regarding celebrity endorsements of Rainbow Kitchen by Bruce Springsteen, Jesse Jackson and Ed Asner are also present, in addition to photographs, videos, slides, and newsletters.
Labor; Social action; Homestead (Pa.); Allegheny County (Pa.); Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Deindustrialization -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Steel industry and trade -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Unemployment -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Iron and steel workers -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.) -- Political activity; Employees -- Recruiting -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Occupational retraining -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Right to labor -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Unemployed -- Services for -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee; Rainbow Kitchen
- Clippings Regarding Steel Decline (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Politics, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 93rd Congress Second Session, Disclosure of Corporate Ownership, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "The FBI is in Town" The Grand Jury Project (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Federation for Progress "Jobs, Peace & Equality" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Committees, Unions, Projects, Groups, etc. Regarding Steel (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Publications Regarding Steel, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Coke Over Conference, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Copies of Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bob Anderson's Records for use Against Company Discipline (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Eminent Domain and Industry (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Conference on Unemployment, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Leaflets, etc., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bob Anderson, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Steel, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Steel Summaries, Assessments, Data, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Coke Oven Commission, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Publications, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Copies of Newspaper Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous USWA Alerts, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Nuclear Regulatory Commission (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Leftist Steel Workers Publications (Box 2, Folder 14)
- USWA Local 1397 Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miners Strikes (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Local 1219 (ET Works) "Uniter" and Problems at ET, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Local 1219 Rank and File Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Local 1219 "Ammo" (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Local 1219 Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Publications on the Steel Industry (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings Regarding Political-Economic Recession, Reaganomics, and Re-elections, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Food Bank (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Steel Valley Unemployment Center, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mortgage Delinquency Taskforce Meeting, January 11, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- Newspaper Clippings (copies), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee Articles (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Bob Anderson Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee Notebook (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Political Pamphlets, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Leaflets, Pamphlets, etc. Regarding Unemployment and Unity, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Rallies, Marches, Meetings, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Assistance Programs, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Pittsburgh Magazine, March 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "People & Power" Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 15)
- The Industrial North: Select Proceedings of the IUP Conference on Industry and Society, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings (copies), 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Mellon Bank, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Steel and Religion, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Steel Industry Information, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Testimonies, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Union Information, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- New Democratic Movement, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Communist Workers' Party, USA 3rd National Congress (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Documents in Preparation for the 3rd Party Congress, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Articles Regarding Local Power in California (Box 5, Folder 4)
- "Capitalism, Culture and the Current Crisis in the United States" by Anthony Mansueto, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- US and International Economy (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Bob Anderson Personal Mailing/Phone List for Unemployed Era, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Program Drafts for the New Democratic Movement, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Correspondence Regarding Executive Committee Meetings (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Fundamentals of Political Economy, Vol. I-II, 1974 (Box 5, Item 1)
- The 80's Theoretical Journal of the Communist Workers Party U.S.A., Vol. I No.1, Vol. II No.3, Special Edition (Box 5, Item 2)
- The True Story of the Greensboro Massacre by Paul C. and Sally A. Bermanzohn (Box 5, Item 3)
- The Eighties, Vol. III No. 4, Vol. IV No. 1-2 (Box 5, Item 4)
- Soldiers and Strikers by Vincent Pinto, 1974 (Box 5, Item 5)
- A Tribute to Florence Reece (Box 5, Item 6)
- "Metalworkers in South Africa", 1984 (Box 5, Item 7)
- "Build Racial Harmony and Economic Cooperation toward the Dream of Equality", 1987 (Box 5, Item 8)
- Officers' Report to the UMWA 47th Constitutional Convention, 1976 (Box 5, Item 9)
- Workers Viewpoint Journal 5, August 1978 (Box 5, Item 10)
- National Bulletins (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Coal Miners Strike and DRUM (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Socialism (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Iran (Box 6, Folder 4)
- African Liberation Support Committee (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Ku Klux Klan (Box 6, Folder 6)
- First Pittsburgh Communist Workers Organization Fliers (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Socialist Workers Party (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Bob Anderson Work History (Box 6, Folder 9)
- National Steel and Shipbuilding Company (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Communist Workers Party Recruitment (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Rallies and Movements (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Summaries of Local Reports (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Bob Anderson Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Clippings Regarding US in El Salvador (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Files (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "Trilateralism" by New York Circus, 1980 (Box 6, Item 1)
- New Democratic Movement National Bulletin, Spring 1987 (Box 6, Item 2)
- "The Post Industrial Society: New Democratic Movement Position Paper on the Economy & Strategy for Change" (Box 6, Item 3)
- Intercom, Vol. I No.1-2 (Box 6, Item 4)
- The New Democrat, Vol. I No. 1,6,8-10 (Box 6, Item 5)
- The Expert Red, Vol. I No.1-3, Vol. II No. 1-3 (Box 6, Item 6)
- Joseph and Eugenia Jurich vs. David Graffius, Bob Anderson Subpoena, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bob Anderson "El Salvador" (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Clippings Regarding East Europe (Box 7, Folder 3)
- US Foreign Policy Clippings (Box 7, Folder 4)
- USSR Clippings (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Libya Clippings (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Cops Clippings (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Mellons Clippings (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Communist Party of the USA Clippings (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Reindustrialization Clippings (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Draft Resistance Clippings (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Economics and Capitalism Clippings (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Catalog Books (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Post-Gazette Outstanding Citizen Award (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Unemployment Data (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Rainbow Coalition and Jesse Jackson (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Soviet Union (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Political Economy (Box 7, Folder 18)
- United Steel Workers of America (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Clippings Regarding the Unemployed (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Economy Clippings (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Clippings Regarding Peace (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Tax Clippings (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Clippings Regarding Foreign Policies (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Election Clippings (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Dual Power Electoral Clippings (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Homestead Boro/Council (Box 7, Folder 28)
- The 80's Theoretical Journal of the Communist Workers Party U.S.A., Vol. II No. 2 (Box 7, Item 1)
- Rainbow Kitchen Log, May 1989-February 1990 (Box 7, Item 2)
- Chalich Campaign and Rainbow Kitchen Log, November 1989-June 1990 (Box 7, Item 3)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Citation by the Pennsylvania House of Representatives to Bob Anderson, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- USWA 50th Anniversary Calendar, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Memorabilia, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Steelabor, Vol. 49 No. 7-9; Vol. 50 No. 1,2,6; Vol. 51 No. 2-7, 10; Vol. 52 No. 1-8; Vol. 53 No. 1,2,5; Vol. 54 No. 2-4, 6 (Box 9, Item 1)
- "Rise Up Against the Klan!" by Libby Wilson and Tamara Johnson, 1980 (Box 9, Item 2)
- Officers' Report, USWA 22nd Constitutional Convention, 1984 (Box 9, Item 3)
- "Forging a Future" Report of the Convention Committee on the Future Directions of the Union, 1984 (Box 9, Item 4)
- American Heritage, February-March 1986 (Box 9, Item 5)
- "The Class Struggle in Steel" by Art Shields (Box 9, Item 6)
- USWA Policy Resolutions of the 23rd Constitutional Convention, 1986 (Box 9, Item 7)
- "Fighting Root Causes of Unemployment" by the Southern Neighborhood Network, 1983 (Box 9, Item 8)
- "The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions" by AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, 1985 (Box 9, Item 9)
- "Phil Murray: The Architect of Industrial Unionism" (Box 9, Item 10)
- "Responding to Economic Dislocation", 1986 (Box 9, Item 11)
- The Steelworkers Oldtimer, Vol. XI No. 1,3 (Box 9, Item 12)
- Owners at Work, Vol. I No. 2 (Box 9, Item 13)
- "American Tragedy-American Hope", 1986 (Box 9, Item 14)
- "USWA Lockout at USX" USX Special Report (Box 9, Item 15)
- Mike Dukakis Campaign Flyer (Box 9, Item 16)
- The AFL-CIO American Federationist, Vol. 94 No. 5 (Box 9, Item 17)
- PHLF News, No.103 (Box 9, Item 18)
- In These Times, Vol. 11 No.36 (Box 9, Item 19)
- National Bulletin, Vol. VII No. 3,5,6 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Communist Party of the USA Summation of the First Sit-Down Strike, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- New Democratic Movement National Bulletin (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Reference Materials Volumes 1-3, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous New Democratic Movement Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
- New Democratic Movement Chapter Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Articles and Reports (Box 10, Folder 7)
- New Democratic Movement National Board (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 9)
- The Black Worker and the American Labor Movement by Thomas R. Brooks (Box 10, Item 1)
- "Wildcat: Dodge Truck", 1974 (Box 10, Item 2)
- "Our Lives are at Stake; Shell Strike 1973" by Barry Weisberg (Box 10, Item 3)
- "Sixty Articles on Work Methods" by Mao Tse-tung, 1958 (Box 10, Item 4)
- The 80's Theoretical Journal of the Communist Workers Party U.S.A., Vol. I No. 1-3, Special Edition, Vol. II No.1 (Box 10, Item 5)
- "The German Peasants' Revolutionary War of 1524-1525" by Paul Michel (Box 10, Item 6)
- "Women Hold Up Half the Sky" (Box 10, Item 7)
- "Workers Viewpoint: The Dodge Revolutionary Union Movement", 1978 (Box 10, Item 8)
- "The Case of the People Against Standard Oil" by Alan S. Miller (Box 10, Item 9)
- The Afro-American National Question Vol. II (Box 10, Item 10)
- The Eighties, Vol. III No. 4 (Box 10, Item 11)
- "The Current Revolutionary Situation: Our Tasks" by Phil Thomson, 1982 (Box 10, Item 12)
- The Bulletin, Vol. II No. 1-4 (Box 10, Item 13)
- The East is Red Record in Chinese (Box 10, Item 14)
- Going to Shaoshan in the Rays of the Morning Sun Record in Chinese (Box 10, Item 15)
- The Freedom Voice Vol. II No. 3 (Box 10, Item 16)
- "The Post Industrial Society" (Box 10, Item 17)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Homestead Housing- History and Proposals by Bob Anderson (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Labor Articles and Flyers (Box 11, Folder 3)
- National Guard Issue (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Owners at Work, Vol. I No. 1 (Box 11, Item 1)
- GI Revolts: The Breakdown of the U.S. Army in Vietnam by Richard Boyle (Box 11, Item 2)
- 1219 Rank & File Bulletin, Vol. III No. 2 (Box 11, Item 3)
- "Metasa: A History of Workers' Struggle in a Nicaraguan Steel Mill" by Alice and Staughton Lynd (Box 11, Item 4)
- "A Study of Housing in Homestead/Munhall 613-645 9th Avenue" by Deborah M. Ehrlich and Gordon A. Davidson, 1983 (Box 11, Item 5)
- "From Racism to Counter-Revolution" by the National Organization for an American Revolution, 1981 (Box 11, Item 6)
- Malon Wilkus, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Various Articles and Clippings (Box 12, Item 1)
- Miscellaneous Documents Regarding the 1986 and 1988 Elections (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Petitions for Office of Delegate to the Democratic National Convention (Box 13, Folder 2)
- National Rainbow Coalition (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Jesse Jackson for President, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Clippings Regarding 1988 Election and Rainbow Kitchen (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
- Middle East and Elections, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Bob Anderson Pins from Jesse Jackson Exploratory Committee (Box 13, Item 1)
- "Meet Jesse Jackson's Labor Delegates" Flyer (Box 13, Item 2)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 14, Folder 1)
- USX Homestead Works (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Plant Closings (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Clippings (copies) Regarding USX and Plant Closings (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Pittsburgh High Technology, 1988 (Box 14, Item 1)
- Pennsylvania Economic Revitalization Fund, 1987 (Box 14, Item 2)
- Business Resource Directory (Box 14, Item 3)
- Industrial Services Program (Box 14, Item 4)
- Federation for Industrial Retention and Renewal NEWS, Vol. II No. 1 (Box 14, Item 5)
- Act Creating the Pennsylvania Industrial Development Finance Corporation, 1987 (Box 14, Item 6)
- Fascists (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
- New Solidarity Newspaper (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Denominational Ministry Strategy (DMS) (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
- DMS Regarding Mellon Bank and Senator Ed Zemprelli (Box 15, Folder 6)
- DMS Clippings (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Confessing Synod Ministries Newsletter, May-August 1988, Vol. I No. 9-12, Vol. II No. 3,4,7 (Box 15, Item 1)
- Voice of the Valley, December 1988, February 1990 (Box 15, Item 2)
- Executive Intelligence Review, Vol. XII No. 31,33, Vol. XIII No. 1-4,6,8 (Box 15, Item 3)
- Update on Anti-Semitic & Racist Intervention in the Farm Protest Movement, January 1986 (Box 15, Item 4)
- The Public Eye, Vol. III Issues 1,2, Vol. IV Issues 3,4 (Box 15, Item 5)
- National Caucus of Labor Committees (Box 15, Item 6)
- The New Federalist, Vol. V No. 12 (Box 15, Item 7)
- American Almanac, Vol. XVI No. 37 (Box 15, Item 8)
- "Global Showdown: The Russian Imperial War Plan for 1988" by the National Democratic Policy Committee, 1985 (Box 15, Item 9)
- The Book on Pittsburgh by DMS, 1985 (Box 15, Item 10)
- Fusion, May-June 1985 (Box 15, Item 11)
- Unity, Vol. VIII No. 11 (Box 15, Item 12)
- Rainbow Kitchen Clippings (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Bob Anderson Resignation, September 10, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Rainbow Kitchen Activities (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Minimum Wage Rally, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Pittsburgh Celebrity Rib Eat-Off (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Dolores Patrick and Cities in Schools Program, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Roughing It at Pitt Activity (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Activities: Contras (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Activities: Rainbow Kitchen Van (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Activities: Rockin' Rainbow Concert (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Activities: KKK (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Activities: Public Relations (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Rainbow Kitchen Citation (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Does Anyone Care? (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Donor Option (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Rainbow Kitchen Expand Services (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Theresa Chalich in Nicaragua (Box 16, Folder 17)
- District Election Coalition Victorious Carl Redwood, Jr., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Holiday Events, 1985-1987 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Ed Asner Visit to Rainbow Kitchen (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Bruce Springsteen Donation, Valley Mirror, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Bruce Springsteen Donation, Star Gazette, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Bruce Springsteen Donation, CMU Focus, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Bruce Springsteen Donation, Post-Gazette, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 24)
- "Hunger in Steel Valley" in Steel Labor Magazine, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Joblessness, Doctors Taskforce, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 26-27)
- "Looking for Work?" Job Bank Flyer (Box 16, Folder 28)
- "We Need Work" Job Bank Flyer (Box 16, Folder 29)
- "Do You Need a Job" Job Bank Flyer (Box 16, Folder 30)
- Job Bank Infrastructure (Box 16, Folder 31)
- "Living and Dying With Steel" Job Bank, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 32)
- "Towns Fight to Survive" Job Bank, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Sheriff Sale Strapped Owners, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Sheriff Sale Sweating it Out, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 35)
- Sheriff Sale Tips on Saving Home (Box 16, Folder 36)
- Rainbow Kitchen Shaky Future, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 37)
- Judge Salmon and Rape (Box 16, Folder 38)
- Rainbow Kitchen Leaders Arrested, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 39)
- Bridges, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 40)
- Quotes (Box 16, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous Articles (Box 16, Folder 42)
- Addresses (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Unemployment Center Daily Messages, June 26-August 27, 1984 (Box 17, Item 1)
- Unemployment Center Daily Messages, April 10-July 30, 1985 (Box 17, Item 2)
- Rainbow Kitchen Daily Messages, November 30, 1984-April 4, 1985 (Box 17, Item 3)
- Rainbow Kitchen Daily Messages, November 1, 1985-April 23, 1986 (Box 17, Item 4)
- Rainbow Kitchen Daily Messages, April 24-September 19, 1986 (Box 17, Item 5)
- "Hunger in Allegheny County", 1986 (Box 17, Item 6)
- "Trouble in Electric Valley: Local Leaders Assess the Difficult Future of Their Community", 1986 (Box 17, Item 7)
- "Steel People: Survival and Resilience in Pittsburgh's Mon Valley", 1986 (Box 17, Item 8)
- Rainbow Kitchen Grant Proposal to Mellon Bank Foundation for a Feasibility Study, 1987 (Box 17, Item 9)
- Background Papers United Way of Allegheny County, 1987 (Box 17, Item 10)
- Decision Package United Way of Allegheny County, 1987 (Box 17, Item 11)
- United Way Priorities: Analyses of Community Problems and Blueprint for Action, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Item 12)
- Final Report on Homelessness in Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 17, Item 13)
- Rainbow Kitchen Food Pantry Survey Report, June 1988 (Box 17, Item 14)
- "When Unemployment Strikes: The Impact on Women in Families", 1988 (Box 17, Item 15)
- Women's Agenda's Women's and Children's Budget FY 1988-1989 (Box 17, Item 16)
- Evaluation of the Unemployed Council of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1989 (Box 17, Item 17)
- "The Hard Times Aren't Over: Basic Information on the Status of Working People" (Box 17, Item 18)
- Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Turtle Creek Mental Health/Mental Retardation Newsletter, March 1987 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Homestead Unemployment Center Survey (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Steel Valley Conference on Governments (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Steel-Iron Wills Sapped Dying Industry (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Steel Valley United for Economic Progress (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Summer Students, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
- Strategic Plan (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Shirt Orders and Information (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Slide Show Script (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Special Events: Harambee Festival (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Sheriff Sale (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Shelter- Emergency Shelter (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Research Study RKCC (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Road Jobs- JOB Program (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Renewal, Inc. Community Services for Offenders (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Letters to Rainbow Kitchen (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Racial Justice (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Provider Council- Direct Service- Hunger Taskforce (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Product Line (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Office Equipment (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Nuclear (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Public Relations- Personalities at Rainbow Kitchen (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Public Relations (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Philadelphia Unemployment Project (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Purchase Orders (Box 18, Folder 27)
- Homestead Unemployment Center Press Releases (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Rainbow Kitchen Press Releases (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Pittsburgh Magazine (Box 18, Folder 30)
- Pennsylvania Unemployment Network (Box 18, Folder 31)
- Pennsylvania Alliance for Jobs and Energy (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Dolores Patrick Personal Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Program to Aid Citizen Enterprise (Box 18, Folder 34)
- Homestead Unemployment Center Originals (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Opportunities Industrial Center and Homestead Unemployment (Box 18, Folder 36)
- Graphics for Newsletter (Box 18, Folder 37)
- New Heritage House (Box 18, Folder 38)
- NAACP (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Mortgage Campaign Articles (Box 18, Folder 40)
- Minimum Wage (Box 18, Folder 41)
- Military- Jobs (Box 18, Folder 42)
- Homestead Unemployment Center- Members List (Box 18, Folder 43)
- Meetings- Minutes of Rainbow Kitchen (Box 18, Folder 44)
- Meetings- Homestead Unemployment Center (Box 18, Folder 45)
- Articles on Homestead Unemployment Center (Box 18, Folder 46)
- Mon-Valley Commission Taskforce (Box 18, Folder 47)
- Media Contacts (Box 18, Folder 48)
- Legislators (Box 18, Folder 49)
- Murals (Box 18, Folder 50)
- Methodist Union of Social Agencies, Inc. (Box 18, Folder 51)
- Monte Carlo- "Thank You" Letters (Box 18, Folder 52)
- Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee (Box 18, Folder 53)
- Donations- Clint Wandel (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Rainbow Kitchen Index (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Senator Edward Zemprelli Picket (Box 19, Folder 3)